<Document>
  # Corporate Agents

  [color=#ac3a0d]An elite agent sent to infiltrate and complete missions onboard various stations.[/color]

  Only select command members can become corporate agents: the Quartermaster, Chief Engineer, and Research Director.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PosterLegitEnlist" Caption="Enlist now!"/>
  </Box>

  Corporate Agents are tasked with retrieving items, testing weak points, sabotaging, or assassinating targets who know too much.

  Despite their deep connections to Nanotrasen/Central Command, they rarely receive help and are abandoned if caught.
  Corporate agents should avoid causing excessive disruption, [color=red][bold]as corporations want to avoid bad press.[/bold][/color]

  ## How they play

  Unlike Traitors, Corporate Agents have limited freedom in their objectives.
  First and foremost, [color=red][bold] they should not be causing more damage than necessary! [/bold][/color]
  Corporate Agents must complete missions while maintaining their disguise as command members.
  It wouldn't be very productive if the station fell apart due to them not doing their job as a head of staff, now would it?

  [bold] Most people don't react well to finding out one of their closest allies is a spy. [/bold]

  ## Objectives

  Corporate Agents receive objectives at the start of the round, often involving traitors or other heads of staff.
  Objectives typically include stealing items or eliminating targets who oppose the corporation or know sensitive information.
  Sometimes someone's been talking against the corporation, or they've heard things they really shouldn't have.

  Agents may also need to handle suspected syndicate spies discreetly, as corporations aim to maintain appearances and avoid public violations of space law.
  [bold]Corporate Agents are here to resolve these issues.[/bold]

  ## Equipment

  Corporate Agents start with an uplink containing 25 telecrystals.
  These corporations usually don't have an abundance of Telecrystals to spare even for their most elite agents.
  Use them wisely.
  Agents must carefully manage their purchases and utilize resources as command members.

  [color=red][bold]You didn't spend all this time infiltrating and gaining trust with nothing to show for it right?[/bold][/color]



  [textlink="For more information on how to play it look in the traitor tab." link="Traitors"]
</Document>
