<Document>
  # Devil

  [color=#ff0000]A devilish trickster with a silver tongue has been making deals.[/color]

  A devil is an entity originating from some ungodly dimension far, far away from our own.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PaperDevilContract" Caption="Contract"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingUniformJumpsuitDevil" Caption="Devilish Attire"/>
  </Box>

  Unlike most depictions in media, a devil isn't easy to find at a glance. There's no fire and brimstone, no pitchfork and screaming. The easiest way to tell is that red glow in their eyes, and sometimes the horns or tail.
  [bold] Not everyone with a tail or horns is a devil, that's just specist! [/bold]

  ## Contracts

  The bread and butter of a devil is their [color=darkred]contracts[/color]. When signing a contract, various effects can be applied onto an entity.

  Contracts are indestructible once signed, there's no going back once pen touches parchment.

  The particular effect of a contract changes depending on which [bold] clauses [/bold] are written on it.
  Effects can be applied to the Contractor, the Devil, or the Contractee, the signer.

  Prefixing a [bold]clause[/bold] with either "Contractee:" or "Contractor:" will dictate who it applies to.

  A [bold] Clause [/bold] is a concept or thing that one of the parties is giving up, either to the other or destroying it entirely.

  Example:
  <Box>
    Contractee: Weakness Contractee: Soul
  </Box>

  In the above contract, the contractee is giving up their weakness and the rights to their soul.
  Giving up your weakness will grant you massive resistance to all damage types, but giving up your soul could have unforeseen consequences.

  ## Contract Weight

  Every contract has a weight associated with it, which can be viewed by inspecting it.
  Contracts with an uneven weight (below zero) cannot be signed.

  Each clause has its own weight value.
  As a general rule of thumb, the better the clause is for the contractee the higher the weight will be.

  This effectively means you have to balance good clauses with bad clauses.
  [italic] It's important to note that there is no limit on how many bad clauses you can put on one contract, always read the fine-print! [/italic]

  ## Selling your soul?

  Selling your soul is a fickle thing; and usually what most devils are after.
  As a devil, your main objective is to collect as many souls as possible. The more souls you gain, the more powerful you become.

  As a contractee, selling your soul has consequences.
  - Without a soul, you will be un-revivable on death.
  - You cannot make any more deals after selling your soul.
  - You will be marked as "Condemned", which could have other consequences.

  ## Dealing with the devil

  The contractee is not the only person that can be tricked.
  Contract weight is applied [bold] no matter who the effect applies to [/bold]

  This means if you can trick a devil to sign a paper negatively affecting them, you can get some positive clauses for free!

  [textlink="Learn more about each clause." link="DevilClauses"]
</Document>
