<Document>
  # Doodon Buildings
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DoodonTownHall" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PapaDoodon" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  ## Town Hall
  The doodon town hall is the heart of the doodon village. It keeps track of population, buildings, and housing capacity. Without the town hall, doodon buildings will cease to function.
  [color=yellow]Housing capacity[/color] is the limiting factor of how many doodons can live in the village. If there are more houses than a specific doodon, then you can spend resin at a house to respawn that doodon.
  If there are greater or equal doodons to houses, then no more doodons can spawn.

  ## Houses:
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DoodonDwelling" Caption="+2 Worker Housing"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WorkerDoodon" Caption="Uses 1 Worker Housing"/>
  </Box>
  ### Dwelling
  Dwellings serve as housing for workers. Each dwelling provides two housing for workers, and spawns one when built. Respawning one worker costs 1 resin.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DoodonWarriorHut" Caption="+1 Warrior Housing"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WarriorDoodon" Caption="Uses 1 Warrior Housing"/>
  </Box>
  ### Warrior Hut
  Huts provide housing for warriors, and produce one when built. Each hut provides one housing for warriors. Respawning one warrior costs 3 resin.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DoodonPasture" Caption="+3 Moodon Housing"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Moodon" Caption="Uses 1 Moodon Housing"/>
  </Box>
  ### Pasture
  Pastures house three moodons, and spawn one when built. Moodons can milked or grinded for omnizine, and can serve as good trade material. Spawning one moodon costs 1 resin.

  ## Refiners:
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DoodonMetalRefiner" Caption="3 Steel = 1 Resin"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DoodonGlassRefiner" Caption="3 Glass = 1 Resin"/>
  </Box>
  Refiners provide another source of resin. Refiners take time, so it might be wise to build multiple of each.

  ## Workshops:

  ### Gem Cutter:
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DoodonGemCutter" Caption="5 Resin = 1 Gem"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DoodonGem" Caption="$$$"/>
  </Box>
  Refines resin into a valuable gem. This gem has no use to the doodons, but can serve as trade material.

  ### Shieldsmith:
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DoodonShieldsmith" Caption="3 Resin = 1 Shield"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DoodonShield" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  Presses resin into a cruddy shield.

  ### Swordsmith:
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DoodonSwordsmith" Caption="3 Resin = 1 Sword"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DoodonSword" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  Smiths resin into a surprisingly sharp sword
  
</Document>
