<Document>
  # Heretic Curses

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CodexMorbus"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="HereticPhylactery"/>
  </Box>

  Curses can be applied to any living person except for heretics, ghouls or wizards.
  The main source of the curses is [color=yellow]Codex Morbus[/color] - tier 2 heretic side knowledge.

  ## Codex Morbus

  Can be transmuted from a corpse and [color=yellow]Codex Cicatrix[/color] on a rune after researching respective knowledge.
  Allows heretics to draw runes and drain influences faster, but more importantly, it provides the ability to apply curses on other people.

  Alt-click transmutation rune with your codex or using context menu to open curse window.
  Either a puddle of victim's blood or an item with DNA should be present on the rune. Curses applied from blood have longer effect, scaling with amount of blood on the rune.
  You can select one victim from the list to curse them temporarily. Remember to select the curse first.

  ## List of curses

  - \[ [color=red]Curse of Corrosion[/color] \] - Causes victim to vomit constantly and take some poison damage.
  - \[ [color=red]Curse of Paralysis[/color] \] - Paralyses victim's legs, forcing them prone and slowing them down.
  - \[ [color=red]Curse of Flames[/color] \] - Burns victim occasionally.
  - \[ [color=red]Curse of Amok[/color] \] - Forces victim to attack other people unintentionally.
  - \[ [color=red]Curse of Blindness[/color] \] - Blinds the victim.
  - \[ [color=red]Curse of Fragility[/color] \] - Doubles all damage dealt to the victim, from any source. This curse is silent and your victim won't be alerted.

  ## Phylactery of Damnation

  A handy tool, made from a pool of blood and a beaker on the rune. Available for free for all heretics.
  Can be used to extract up to 10u of blood from victims, even at range. Be aware that your victim would still feel a tiny prick.
  Blood can either be transferred into other container, or spilled on the ground and used in rituals or curses.
</Document>
