<Document>
# Slasher

[color=#ac3a0d]An unstoppable 80's terror driven by vengeance, dread, and synth beats echoing through dark maintenance.[/color]

The Slasher is a relentless horror that stalks isolated crew, harvesting their souls and growing stronger with every victim. It thrives on fear, appearing and vanishing between flickers of light and fresh trails of blood.

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingHeadHatSlasherMask" Caption="Mask"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SlasherMachete" Caption="Machete"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SlasherMeatSpike" Caption="Meat Spike"/>
</Box>

  Unlike most midround antagonists the slasher starts off weak. For every soul they steal they gain that much more strength. If left unchecked they can quickly become a terrifying force.

  ## Core Loop
  1. Find isolated targets.

  2. Incapacitate and absorb their soul.

  3. Repeat.

  4. Once you gain enough souls you can really start embodying the 80's slasher vibes.

  ## Abilities

  [bold]Machete Summon[/bold] – You can always call your signature weapon back. This is a great skill if you lose your weapon or want to throw it at someone for some quick damage.

  [bold]Soul Steal[/bold] – Can only be used on an incapicated or otherwise restrained target. For every soul stolen you gain more defense and increased damage. It is much more effective on alive targets. Victims become [italic]soulless[/italic] and receive a random negative devil clause.

  [bold]Massacre[/bold] – An incredibly strong move that's tied to your special machete. When first used you deal much less damage but the more hits you deal the more damage you deal. After a certain point you will start chopping off the victims limbs and at the 13th hit you decapitate them. Missing resets the combo.

  [bold]Regeneration / Slasherium[/bold] – An incredibly robust source of healing. It rejuvanates you and takes off any restraints. It comes at the cost of an incredibly long cooldown.

  [bold]Blood Trail[/bold] – Leave a trail of blood in your wake. It also plays some music. Spooky!

  [bold]Incorporeal / Corporealization[/bold] – Dissappear and reappear from the material realm. This is your main source of traversal. You cannot use it while seen. Extremely limited but very powerful. Blocks cooldowns from going down while in jaunt.

  [bold]Possession[/bold] – Temporarily take control of a victims body. Mindshields block it.

  [bold]Meat Spike[/bold] – You can summon a meatspike that you can use to trap your victims in. It is incredibly useful for stealing souls and preventing people from running away.

  [bold]Stagger Area[/bold] – You slow down everyone that's near you for a short amount of time. Very useful for getting the jump on people.

  ## Crew Tips
  [bold]Do not wander alone.[/bold].
  - They are relatively weak when they first appear on the station.
  - When they steal souls they become much more tankier and deal that much more damage.
  - If you get the drop on them do not let them out of your sight. If you see them they can't escape.
  - They are weak to holy. Get the chaplain to help out if you're running low on forces.
  - Tinfoil hats and mindshields prevent possessions!
  - Upon 15 souls stolen an announcement plays to warn the crew.
  - They have no crit state.

  [color=red][bold]You are the legend of the midnight massacre—make it feel like one.[/bold][/color]
</Document>
