<Document>
  # Slaughter Demon

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BaseMobSlaughterDemon" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Slaughter Demons are large, armour-plated monsters sent from the depths of hell to steal the souls of the crew in a very violent fashion.
  They can use blood to travel quickly, possess a pair of large blades in place of arms, and can fully heal by eating downed crewmembers.

  ## Summoning a Being from Hell

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingHeadHatWizard" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  There are a two ways a Slaughter Demon may enter the station to terrorize it. It can be summoned onto the overworld with a mystical summoning item by a Wizard foolish enough to do so, or through a Midround roll.
  Both options let spirits take over the role of a blood thirsty spawn of Satan.

  ## How to play as the slaughter demon, by a slaughter demon

  LISTEN, DEMON. [color=red]ALL YOU HAVE TO DO IS KILL[/color]. RIP THEIR GUTS OUT, DRINK THEIR BLOOD... YOU KNOW, DAILY UNDERWORLD ACTIVITIES.
  JUST GO OUT THERE AND HIT PEOPLE, MAKE THEM BLEED. YOU UNDERSTAND???

  BUT REMEMBER, DEVILS ARE OUR HOMIES SO DON'T GO ATTACKING THEM FOR NO REASON!

  OH, AND IF YOU SEE A LAUGHTER DEMON THEN MAKE FUN OF THEM, OR MAKE THEIR DAY WORSE... SATAN TOLD US THAT WE CAN'T KILL THEM, SOOOO... DEAL WITH THEM FOR THE TIME BEING!
  HOW CAN THEY NOT LOVE BLOOD AS MUCH AS WE DO????

  ## BASIC ABILITIES

  - BLOOD JAUNTING

  SPREADING BLOOD ALL THROUGH THE HALLWAYS (DRAGGING A CORPSE WHILE SLASHING IT) WILL HELP YOU IN THE LONG RUN, TRUST ME.
  HAVING THE ABILITY TO TELEPORT ANYWHERE PROVES TO BE PRETTY USEFUL.

  - CORPSE FEEDING

  NO SHAME ON TAKING A BITE ONCE YOU DRAG THEM TO HELL, MY FRIEND.
  IT'S YOUR ONLY WAY OF HEALING, SHORT OF A HUMAN PATCHING YOU UP. NOT ONLY IS A HUMAN GIVING YOU MEDICAL HELP A DISGRACE TO ALL DEMONKIND,
  BUT IF YOU EVEN ADMIT THAT YOU'RE CLOSE TO DYING THEY'LL PROBABLY JUST KILL YOU ANYWAY, YOU STUPID IDIOT DEMON.

  - JAUNT KILLING

  WE ARE SLOW, OKAY? IT TURNS OUT HAVING A SUIT OF INFERNAL ARMOR GLUED TO US IS PRETTY HEAVY. LUCKILY, YOU CAN GET SOME PRETTY EASY KILLS JUMPING OUT OF BLOOD AS THE BLOOD WILL GIVE YOU A SPEED BOOST.
  FANTASTIC COMBO, JUMP OUT OF BLOOD, ATTACK, TRY TO GET IN A FEW, AND THEN RETREAT TO THE BLOOD FOR ANOTHER SPEED ATTACK.
  REALLY THE ONLY WAY YOU'RE REALISTICALLY GOING TO STOP A SHOTGUN WIELDING ASSHOLE, SO PRACTICE MAKES PERFECT.

  ANYWAYS, I'M TOO BUSY WITH DRINKING SOME CLOWN'S BLOOD RIGHT NOW, SO I'LL SEE YA LATER IN HELL.
</Document>
