<Document>
## The Xenomorph Life Cycle

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="XenomorphEgg" Caption=""/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobXenomorphFaceHugger" Caption=""/>
</Box>

  The lowliest form of Xenomorph is the humble [color=#FFBF00]facehugger[/color], the only type of xenomorph not usually player-controlled.
  [color=#FFBF00]Facehuggers[/color] hatch from eggs laid by Queens, and on their own simply meander around.
  If they come close to appropriate prey, typically humans or monkeys, they will launch themselves at their targets, ripping off most (but not all) forms of face protection and aggressively violating their victim's esophagus.

  The facehugger dies afterwards, but their target will have an alien larva planted inside them,
  which will fatally burst out of their chest after some time.
  Note that facehuggers act as pseudo-items, and can be picked up by mature xenomorphs to throw at prey.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobXenomorphLarva" Caption=""/>
</Box>

  Also known as chestbursters, [color=#E97451]Larva[/color] are violently born from the bodies of those who fall prey to facehuggers.
  When a larva is born, a random ghost player takes control of it, joining the xenomorphs and adding to their growing army.

  [color=#E97451]Larva[/color] are relatively helpless, having no real offensive capability; instead, they must stay alive long enough to grow into an adult xenomorph.
  They can crawl through vents to escape danger, and hide under tables to avoid detection.
  Once they've grown enough, they can become one of three types of xeno:
  - Hunters
  - Sentinels
  - Drones

  ## The xenomorphs
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobXenomorphHunter" Caption=""/>
</Box>

  The offensive backbone of the xenos, [color=#9F2B68]Hunters[/color] move at blistering speed and can tackle down their unlucky opponents for quick stuns.
  Hunters are typically tasked with securing new prey by ventcrawling through the station, facehuggers in hand, looking for lone crew members to throw them at.
  They're also the best class for starting new outposts and spreading plasma weeds, due to their speed.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobXenomorphSentinel" Caption=""/>
</Box>

  Defensive guards of the nest, [color=#5D3FD3]Sentinels[/color] are slower and beefier than Hunters, and can become partially invisible by staying still.
  Their abilities recharge quicker than Hunters', and they usually stay near nests, keeping any captured humans from escaping and protecting the Drones.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobXenomorphDrone" Caption=""/>
</Box>

  An important type of xenomorph, second only to the Queen, [color=#871F78]Drones[/color] are the builders of the xenomorphs.
  They can construct resin walls to block pathways, resin nests to keep prey secured, and other such structures.
  Drones are also the only adult xenomorph capable of further evolution, into a Praetorian.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobXenomorphPraetorian" Caption=""/>
</Box>

  [color=#871F78]Praetorians[/color] share many of the same abilities as Queens, without the ability to lay eggs.
  If none exist on the station, Praetorians can evolve into Queens themselves.
  Each xenomorph colony only has one Queen, and each is a massive engine of destruction, though their real power is in the ability to lay eggs. A nest with no Queen is crippled, and a colony with no Queens, Praetorians or Drones is effectively neutered.
  Both Praetorians and Queens are also incredibly slow, and the only aliens who can't ventcrawl.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobXenomorphQueen" Caption=""/>
</Box>

  The [color=#702963]Queen[/color] is the heart of the hive, laying eggs to expand the colony.

  [bold]Also, it should be noted that all xenos have a 3 shove 15 second stun.[/bold]
</Document>
