<Document>
## Playing as a Xenomorph

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ResinWeedNode" Caption=""/>
</Box>

  ### Initial Spawn and Survival

  When you spawn as a xenomorph, you will always begin as a Larva.
  Larvae are extremely vulnerable, and your sole objective is to survive long enough to evolve.
  Use your hivemind language by pressing L (or language keybind) to communicate with other xenos.

  If you spawn alone, finding safety is critical.
  You can hide under tables and crawl through vents (alt+click) to escape danger.
  Being space-proof also means you can wait safely on the station's exterior.
  Once you have survived long enough on plasma weeds, you can evolve into an adult caste.

  ### Resources and Abilities

  Once you evolve, plasma becomes your primary resource.
  You generate it over time and can spend it to plant weeds.
  Weeds create resin floors that significantly boost your plasma regeneration, so begin planting them immediately to establish territory and accelerate your power.
  Adult xenomorphs share several powerful abilities:
  - Corrosive Acid: A spit that slowly melts walls, doors, and other structures.
  Use it to break into secure areas and reshape the station.
  - Neurotoxin Spit: A ranged attack that stuns your target.
  Ready the ability, then click your target to fire.

  - Innate Abilities: All adults have night vision, can see humans through walls, and can pry open airlocks.

  ### The First Xeno: Becoming the Queen

  If you are the first and only xenomorph, [bold]it is absolutely essential that you evolve into a Drone.[/bold]

  - Your entire goal is to become a Queen as quickly as possible.
  This requires evolving from Drone to Praetorian, and then to Queen.
  Find a secure, hidden location before you evolve, as Praetorians and Queens lose the ability to crawl through vents.
  As the Queen, your main role is to build a nest and lay eggs.
  - Find a Nest: Choose a defensible, out-of-the-way location with room to expand.
  - Secure the Area: Destroy cameras and consider depressurizing the area to make it hostile for human intruders.
  - Lay Eggs Constantly: Your plasma should be almost exclusively used for laying eggs to grow your hive.

  [bold]Click a fully grown egg to open it.[/bold]
  Once you have facehuggers, you can begin hunting.
  Monkeys are easy, defenseless targets.
  For human targets, a thrown facehugger can be an instant incapacitation, but be aware that Medbay can surgically remove the larva.
  Prioritize your own survival above all; if the Queen dies without a successor, the hive is finished.
  In a direct fight, your tail swing is a powerful stun, but it has a long cooldown.
  You are slow and vulnerable to ranged attackers, but deadly in melee.

  ### The Hunter: Aggressive Offense

  If a hive already has a Queen, the Hunter is an excellent choice for an offensive role.
  Your high speed and ability to ventcrawl make you perfect for navigating the station.
  The Hunter's signature ability is the pounce, a long-range leap that heavily stuns a target on impact.
  Be cautious of shields, which will stun you instead.
  Your main tactic is to carry facehuggers from the nest, pounce on an isolated crewmember, apply the facehugger, and drag them away.
  Remember to sabotage the station by destroying machines and ripping open airlocks as you move.

  ### The Sentinel: Defensive Guardian

  The Sentinel is the hive's dedicated defender.
  Your primary role is to guard the nest, protect the Queen, and watch over captured hosts.
  While slower than a Hunter, you are tougher and have larger plasma reserves that recharge faster, allowing for more frequent use of Neurotoxin Spit and Corrosive Acid.
  The Sentinel's key ability is partial invisibility.
  By staying still, you can blend into the resin-covered floors of your nest, making you perfect for ambushing intruders.

  ### The Drone: Hive Architect

  With a Queen already established, the Drone functions as the hive's architect.
  You can construct several key structures to fortify your nest:

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WallResin" Caption=""/>
</Box>

  - Resin Walls: Standard walls to block paths and create chokepoints.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ResinMembrane" Caption=""/>
</Box>

  - Resin Membranes: Durable windows that allow sight in and out of the nest.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ResinNest" Caption=""/>
</Box>

  - Resin Nests: Beds used to secure captured hosts while their larva gestates.
  While not a primary combatant, you must be ready to defend the Queen.

  Crucially, if the Queen dies, a Drone must evolve to replace her.
  If you are the last surviving Drone, your priority is to escape, find a safe place, and begin the evolution process to save the hive.
</Document>
