<Document>
  # Core Rule 13 - Use realistic character names, and do not use names of famous people
  - No names of people or characters from the real world. Even if you switch a few letters around, be original.
  - No titles/honorifics (Exceptions being generational titles like 
  - Must follow all other rules (no slurs/sexual names/etc)
  - Usernames, objects, random characters, very "low effort" names, "meta" names, or otherwise implausible names cannot be used as names. See examples below. 
  - Admin rulings on IC names are final and disputes should be done through the forums, not by refusing to comply with an admin
  - Species have naming conventions that are part of their in-universe culture. These may be subverted if they have sufficient in-character reasoning and effort to explain their non-standard name. Non-standard names are held to higher scrutiny and you may be questioned on why your name breaks these conventions.


Naming Conventions:


  Clowns and mimes are exempt from the prohibition on titles/honorifics and have loosened restrictions on low-effort and implausible names.

  ## Clarification on "Meta" Names
  Meta names are ones that attempt to take advantage of some game mechanic or game design choice. "Urist McHands" is a meta name because it is the default name used for admin-spawned humans. "Operator Whiskey" is a meta name because it follows the naming pattern of nuclear operatives. This rule is not intended to prevent things like nuclear operatives using a fake ID with names that appear to be nuclear operative names if they decide that they want to do that.

  ## Conventions and Examples
  [color=#994444]Bad[/color] cannot be used by any species. [color=#449944]Acceptable[/color] names can be used by any species.

  Humans, Dwarves, Felinids, Vulpkanins, and Harpies should use the Firstname Lastname convention.
  
  Examples
  - Tom Fisher
  - Spacey Chapman
  - Aaron Rikes

  Reptilians should be using the Verb-article-Noun or an Argonian convention.
 
  Examples
  -  Cleans-the-Airlocks
  -  Deekus
  -  Deetum-Ja
  -  Artemis
  -  Rolls-the-Dice

  Diona should have calm, nature-themed, Noun of Noun style names.
  
  Examples
  
  - Petal of Tranquility
  - Garden of Relaxation

  Mothmen should have Latin-sounding names or light-themed names.
  
  Examples
  - Socrates Temnora
  - Sierra Lightseeker
  - James Nightflitter

  Arachnids should have Latin-sounding names.
  
  Examples
  - Argyroneta Reticulatus
  - Loxosceles Domesticus

  Vox use a single name made of random syllables, often with repeating patterns.
  Names should not be excessively long or be so repetitive/convoluted as to be unreadable.

  Examples
  - Hirixashahre
  - Xapikrikrik
  - Chipikirchitchitchitbecretretrer

  Rodentia naming convention goes "last first", the "last" part being a descriptor (Strong, Big-eyed, Trash-eating) and the "first" part either being a simple first name or pet name (Monty, Basil, Nibbles)

  Examples
  - Big Poppy
  - Fast-paws Lily
  - Strong Peanut
  - Big-eyed Basil

  Usernames, objects, random characters, very "low effort" names, "meta" names, or otherwise implausible names are not permitted.
  
  Examples
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] XxRobustxX
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] SDpksSodjdfk
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Lkdsoisgoieun
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] F4ith H3arth
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Greytide
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Passenger
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Urist McHands
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Admin
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Game-Master
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Joe Mamma
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Middle-Aged Man
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Operative Whiskey
</Document>
