<Document>
# IN-GAME & ROLEPLAY RULES -
 
	8. Act at least vaguely like an actual human being on a space station in a low-roleplay (LRP) environment. Do not use text speak or emoticons IC, and do not refer to OOC things like admins in-game. Do not threaten players that you are calling the admins on them. Do not use emotes to bypass speech filters or muteness. You are not required to write a backstory or follow strict procedure; however, you are expected to at least make an effort to act like your role.

	
	9. Don't be a dick. You are playing a multiplayer game with other people who also want to enjoy the game.
     - The arrivals station, shuttle, and general arrivals docking area are completely off-limits to any Structurally hostile activity, including anything that makes the immediate areas inately uninhabitable. Attacking newly spawned players in these areas or damaging/sabotaging these areas is strictly forbidden.

     - THE ROUND IS NOT OVER UNTIL THE END-ROUND SUMMARY APPEARS. KILLING SOMEONE FOR NO REASON BEFORE THIS WILL BE HANDLED ACCORDINGLY.

     - Antagonists have a lot of leeway with this rule and may kill/sabotage as they see fit, however if your behavior degrades the experience for the majority of the server you will be asked to stop. Antagonists are still generally forbidden from causing massive station damage early into the round (less than 30 minutes). For antagonist specific rules, see the "long" form of the rules at wiki.spacestation14.io.

	
	10. Don't harass or target players across rounds for actions in prior rounds or for actions outside of the game (this is referred to as "Metagrudging".)
	
     - Annoying players for IC reasons in the current round is totally fine; doing it across rounds or as a ghost role after they kill you is a dickhead move.

	
	11.[/color] Don't use information gained from outside your character's knowledge to gain an advantage (this is referred to as "Metagaming").
	
     - You remember all events up until you fall unconscious, even after cloning. If you take a ghost role, unless otherwise stated, you DO NOT REMEMBER ANYTHING from your past life.

	
	12.[/color] Follow escalation rules and don't murder someone for slipping you, use common sense.
	
     - You can defend yourself to the extent of protecting your own life.
	
     - Security may use less-lethal force to effect arrests of criminals.
	
     - Don't outright leave people to die if you get in a fight, make an effort to heal them or bring them to Medbay.
	
     - Adminhelp the situation if you think someone is over-escalating.
	
     - Department strikes, revolutions (ex: cargonia and any variation thereof), riots, cults, and any other type of similar largely disruptive behavior are encouraged, but MUST have an at very least semi-valid IC(In-Character) reason or cause. Other than for revolutionary antagonists, these activities should be relatively uncommon. All players, including antagonists other than revolutionaries, MUST obtain admin permission before engaging in this behavior (you are very likely to get permission).

	
	13. Don't immediately ghost or suicide from your role if you do not get antagonist (referred to as "Antag-rolling") or from head roles without notifying your chain of command or administrators.

     - Head of Staff roles help drive rounds. If you need to leave, please admin-help your role and that you are leaving. There is no need to wait for a reply when admin-helping that you need to disconnect as a head role, just let us know; then you're free to disconnect.

	
	14. Don't rush for or prepare equipment unrelated to your job for no purpose other then to have it "just in case" (referred to as "Powergaming").

     - A medical doctor does not need insulated gloves, and the Head of Personnel does not need to give themselves armory access so they can go grab a gun. Have at the least a vague IC reason for needing these things.

     - Don't manufacture weapons, bombs, or death poisons before you know of any reason you would need them.

     - Don't pre-emptively hide antagonist objectives or pre-emptively secure them with higher security then normally required.

	
	15. Intentionally making yourself a major problem/annoyance/disruption for the crew or other players at large while not an antagonist is largely discouraged (referred to as "self-antagging").
    
	 - Don't openly try to cooperate with obvious or known antagonists as a non-antagonist.

	</Document>
