<Document>
## Contraband Guidelines
These guidelines may be referred to when determining the sentencing for a contraband item.


Anything that is not covered in this SoP should be treated according to it's contraband label. For example, an item that isn't covered but is clearly a syndicate item should be treated as Restricted Equipment.



# Minor Contraband
    The Captain or Head of Security may authorize any of these items for a crew member to possess or use. Any minor contraband should be revoked on arrest, without leading to jailtime unless it's a repeated offense.

    Any item used in commision of a crime, but is not normally contraband, may be considered minor contraband and confiscated. An example of such is tools used to break into a secure area.
    
    Anything covered here is treated as Possession of Minor Contraband in spacelaw.

    If an individual requires minor contraband for their job, such as the bartender's shotgun, it cannot be confiscated unless used in a crime.
    
    1. Low capacity firearms, such as double-barrel shotguns or security shell guns.
    
    2. Basic armor, such as standard security vests.
    
    3. Handcuffs, zipties, and any other restraining device.
    
    4. Security utility items, such as flashbangs, bola's or seclights.
    
    5. Basic or improvised melee weapons, such as spears or bats.

    6. Disabler pistol's, telescopic batons, and flashes.
    
    7. Command and Syndicate clothing.

    8. Security glasses, including the BSO secmed glasses.

## Departmental Contraband
    The Captain or relevant department head may authorize the possession and use of any item that is restricted to a department. Departmental contraband should be returned to the relevant department if confiscated.

    Anything covered here is treated as Possession of Restricted Equipment in spacelaw, and should result in brigtime.

    1. Salvage, Engineering, Paramedic, and other department hardsuits.

    2. Lethal ammunition for firearms, including improvised shotgun shells.

    3. Security stun baton's and stinger grenades.

    4. Security truncheons, shields, and Disabler SMGs.

    5. Security riot or Type III bulletproof vests.

    6. PKA's and other Cargo weapons.

    7. Fireaxes and other departmental melee weapons.

## Restricted Weapons
    The Captain and HoS may authorize the possession and use of a restricted weapon. Additionally, anyone in the Security department is allowed to use restricted weaponry when authorized by HoS or Warden. Command staff must get Captain or HoS permission before taking any restricted weaponry from the armory or Security.

    Anything covered here is treated as Possession of Restricted Weaponry in spacelaw, and should result in brigtime.

    1. Any Security firearm.

    2. Any minor or improvised firearm when loaded with lethal ammunition.

    3. Lasers and other energy projectile weapons.

    4. Combat knives, swords, and other lethal blades.

    5. Wonderprods, Energy Katanas, and other specialized non-Syndicate weapons.

    6. Explosive payloads and grenades.

    7. Pipebombs and IEDs.

    8. Security Hardsuits.

## Heretic Items
    Heretic items cannot be authorized by anyone. They may only be used in extreme emergencies

    Most equipment covered in this section is treated as Possession of Restricted Equipment in spacelaw, and should result in brigtime. Confiscated Heretic items must stay in the armory.

    1. Heretic Codex books.

    2. Any item which allows them to use magical abilities, such as Amber Focuses.

    3. Any blades which they could form into a more dangerous weapon.

    4. Heretic armor.

    5. Any other magical items used by the Heretic.

## Syndicate Major Contraband
    Only a CentComm official may authorize the possession of any item made and operated by rival corporations. Said items cannot be used and may only kept as showpieces outside of extreme emergencies.

    Anything covered here is treated as Possession of Restricted Equipment in spacelaw, and should result in brigtime. Confiscated syndicate items must stay in the armory.

    1. CyberSun pens and other Syndicate forgery tools.

    2. Hyperzine injectors, Interdyne cigarettes, Syndicate surgery equipment, and other medical devices, excluding Combat Medkits.

    3. EMAGs, Radio Jammers, and other disruption items.

    4. Contractor Baton's.

    5. Syndicate uplink's, including PDAs containing an open uplink.

    6. Stealth Equipment, including chameleon items and forged IDs.

    7. Chest rigs, Syndicate bags, and other storage units.

    8. Syndicate Operative and Genetic Ancestor radios.

    9. Bloodred magboots, Syndicate jetpacks, and other utility wearables.

    10. Syndicate encryption keys and comms devices.

    11. Basic ammunition and magazines for Syndicate guns.

    12. Syndicate Jaws of Life and other breaching tools.

    13. Syndicate toolboxes and tools.

## Syndicate Weapons
    Syndicate weapons cannot be authorized by anyone. They may only be used in extreme emergencies.

    Anything covered here is treated as Possession of Restricted Weaponry in spacelaw, and should result in brigtime.

    1. Any Syndicate firearm.

    2. Any Syndicate melee weapon.

    3. Syndicate bombs, China Lakes, and other syndicate explosives.

    4. Syndicate Cat, Maggot, and Assault Borg reinforcements.

    5. Explosive ammunition, such as China Lake rounds.

    6. Armor-Piercing ammunition.

    7. Subsonic or silenced ammunition.

    8. Bloored hardsuits and its derivatives.

    9. Raid suits, web vests and other non-hardsuit armor.

    10. Syndicate grenades, including shrapnel grenades. 

    11. Syndicate turrets.

    12. Romerol.

## Minor Drugs
    The Captain or CMO may authorize the use of any drugs. Additionally, a psychiatrist may authorize psychedelic drugs for medical use.

    Anything covered here is treated as Possession of Minor Contraband in spacelaw.

    1. Ephedrine, desoxyephedrine, and any drugs which use either as an ingredient.
    
    2. Psychedelics, such as Space Mirage or LSD.
    
    3. Fentanyl.
    
    4. Atmospheric gasses being used for recreational purposes, mainly Frezon.
    
    5. Nocturine and Chloral Hydrate.

    6. Mute Toxin

    7. Razorium

    7. Any dangerous chemicals not mentioned in the "Toxins and Harmful Chemicals" section below, such as acid's.

## Toxins and Harmful Chemicals
    Any chemicals here may be authorized with the Captains permission. However, they must stay within the chemistry lab unless there is an extreme emergency.

    Any chemicals covered here are treated as Possession of Restricted Equipment in spacelaw, and should result in brigtime. 

    1. Vestine.

    2. Heartbreaker Toxin.

    3. Lexorin.

    4. Lead.

    5. Phlogiston.

    6. CLF3 and other Chemical Bomb's

</Document>