<Document>

  # Capoeira

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CapoeiraManual" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Capoeira, the Syndicate's dance of war originating in Brazil, is a [textlink="martial art" link="MartialArts"] that disguises violence as beauty.
  Swift attacks link into flowing combos, each move faster and harder than the last one, fueled by relentless momentum.

  ## Special abilities

  Capoeira users are better at Grab intent, as successfully grabbing an opponent grants them a brief speed boost.

  ### Capoeira Stance

  You never stop moving while performing the ginga. This makes you very mobile while fighting.

  Through swift motion, Capoeira masters channel speed into energy, with combos being more deadly the faster they run.
  Halt their flow, and their strength will vanish. Their combos, powered by movement, falter when they are prone.

  ### Capoeira Momentum

  Through the flowing, relentless motion of Capoeira, each successful combo restores the user's stamina.
  Every connected strike fuels their endurance, allowing them to fight longer, faster, and harder without pause.

  ### Capoeira Tempo

  Hit or miss, it's just part of the dance! And the best part is about to start!

  A missed attack sharpens the next, reducing its recovery and increasing the damage.

  ## Combo attacks

  ### Push Kick

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookGrab" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookHarm" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookHarm" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Knocks down and pushes opponent away from the user. Doesn't force to drop held items.

  ### Circle Kick

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookDisarm" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookDisarm" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookHarm" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Deals Blunt damage and also slows down the opponent significantly.

  ### Sweep Kick

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookHarm" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookHarm" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookDisarm" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Knocks down and deals Blunt and Stamina damage. Temporarily increases user's attack speed by a bit.
  Cannot be performed if the user is moving too slow.

  ### Spin Kick

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookGrab" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookHarm" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookDisarm" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookHarm" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Deals a lot of Blunt damage and knocks the opponent down. Also makes the user flip. Only works on standing opponents.
  Cannot be performed if the user is moving too slow.

  ### Kick Up

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookDisarm" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookDisarm" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Needs to be targeted at the user themselves. Can be performed while prone. Removes knock down status effect and forces the user to stand up instantly.

</Document>
