<Document>

  # Corporate Judo

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingBeltCorporateJudo" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Corporate Judo, or simply Judo, is a [textlink="martial art" link="MartialArts"] that focuses on restraining your opponent with more
  complex but effective moves. You will see this style most used by Security Officers, as they get access to the belts in their department.
  Harness the art and strike any tider that gets in your way. A good understanding of intents is required.

  ## Special abilities

  Judo users are better at Harm intent, as their unarmed attacks will deal extra damage to the opponent.

  ### Stunbaton Scorn

  A Judo user is unable to use stunbatons. A true master relies on technique, using the
  body’s leverage and strength to subdue, leaving the need for electrified force behind.

  ## Combo attacks

  ### Discombobulate

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookDisarm" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookGrab" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Slows the opponent down and reduces their stamina resistance temporarily.

  ### Eye Poke

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookDisarm" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookHarm" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Blinds the opponent and blurs their vision, regardless of eye protection, and deals some Blunt damage.

  ### Judo Throw

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookGrab" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookDisarm" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Can only be perfomed while standing. Only works on standing opponents, dealing Stamina damage and knocking them down.
  Knockdown duration is affected by their Stamina resistance.

  ### Armbar

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookDisarm" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookDisarm" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookGrab" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Only works on downed opponents. Inflicts Stamina damage, disarms them, and locks them in an armbar until they manage to stand up.
  Armbar works similarly to a knockdown and choke grab, and its duration is affected by their Stamina resistance.

  ### Wheel Throw

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookGrab" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookDisarm" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookHarm" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Only works on opponents locked in an armbar. Flips the opponent over the shoulder,
  inflicting massive Stamina damage, and forces the user back on their feet.

</Document>
