<Document>

  # Close Quarters Combat

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CQCManual" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Close Quarters Combat, or simply CQC, is a [textlink="martial art" link="MartialArts"] that focuses on swiftly and efficiently
  dispatching your target, with simple but powerful combos that lack the more outlandish moves of other martial arts.
  CQC is primarily an aggressive fighting style that focuses on dealing stamina damage to targets - designed to quickly subdue
  opponents and overpower them with pressure technique and crushing blows. This art requires a thorough knowledge of intents.

  It is usually used by Syndicate antagonists, however Chefs also get access to it. In Chef's case, CQC obviously stands
  for Close Quarters Cooking, and Chefs don't cook outside of kitchen, so they are unable to use CQC away from it.

  ## Special abilities

  CQC users are better at Disarm intent, as their shoves will deal extra stamina damage to the opponent.

  ### Neck Snap

  There is no escape from a choke grab of a CQC master. If they are out of stamina, with a single Harm action to the head, the victim's neck breaks,
  killing them instantly. No armor can shield against this deadly precision. The end comes swiftly, and without mercy.

  ## Combo attacks

  ### Slam

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookGrab" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookHarm" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Slams the opponent, knocking them down while dealing Blunt damage. Only works on standing opponents.

  ### Kick

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookHarm" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookHarm" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Knocks the opponent away and deals both Blunt and Stamina damage. If opponent is out of stamina, puts them to sleep.

  ### Restrain

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookGrab" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookGrab" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Locks the opponent into a restraining position, knocking them down while dealing Stamina damage.

  ### Pressure

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookDisarm" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookGrab" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Deals Stamina damage and steals whatever item the opponent is currently holding in their active hand.

  ### Consecutive

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookDisarm" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookDisarm" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookHarm" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Deals a lot of Stamina damage and some Blunt damage to the opponent.

  ### Leg Sweep

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookHarm" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Can only be performed while prone. Knocks the opponent down and forces the user back on their feet, even if they are manually crawling.

</Document>
