<Document>

  # Mimejutsu

  <Box>
      <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MimejutsuManual" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Mimejutsu is a [textlink="martial art" link="MartialArts"] built around a series of precise combos designed to debilitate and control opponents.
  It focuses on misdirection and invisible weapons to disorient targets, applying pressure to critical points to weaken and silence them without relying on brute force.

  Mimejutsu is an aggressive and debilitating fighting style that focuses on precise strikes - designed to quickly subdue targets by breaking bones,
  impairing movement, and shutting down their ability to communicate. This art requires a thorough knowledge of intents.

  ## Special Abilities

  Mimejutsu users are better at Disarm intent, as their shoves will deal extra stamina damage to the opponent.

  ### Riposte

  With lightning reflexes, a mimejutsu master has a chance to parry any incoming melee attack. In that brief moment, the attacker is left vulnerable,
  so the mimejutse master strikes back and stuns them automatically, unless they are also a mimejutsu master. A calculated, deadly response to any assault.

  ### Silent punch

  On a successful hit, there is a chance the strike will target key nerve clusters and muscle groups,
  weakening the target's limbs and slowing their movement for 2 seconds. A subtle yet effective way to gain a tactical advantage.

  ## Combo Attacks

  ### Silent Execution

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookHarm" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookDisarm" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookDisarm" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookHarm" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Delivers a precise, silent strike to a targeted limb. Breaks a bone in the chosen body part. If the bone is already broken, the force of the blow deals 40 Brute damage instead.

  ### Mimechucks

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookDisarm" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookGrab" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  The user strikes the target with an invisible but devastating pair of nunchucks, dealing 60 stamina damage and briefly disorienting them.

  ### Silencer

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookGrab" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookDisarm" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  A swift chop to the throat disrupts the target's ability to speak and move freely. Slows the target for 3 seconds and completely silences them for 10 seconds.

  ### Silent Palm

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookGrab" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookHarm" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  The user channels force into an open-palm strike, releasing a concussive wave of silent energy. Knocks the target back four tiles, deals 20 Brute damage, and slows them for 1 second.

</Document>