<Document>

  # Ninjutsu

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="EnergyKatana" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Ninjutsu is a [textlink="martial art" link="MartialArts"] thoroughly developed by the Spider Clan.
  Space Ninjas are true masters of this technique, yet Space Wizards may also unravel its secrets.
  Remember your four teachings. Never move around loud. Only strike when unseen. Patience prevails, haste fails. Death comes in silence.

  ## Special abilities

  ### Sneak Attack

  In the shadow of stillness, the Ninja's strike shall echo with the force of two, dealing massive extra damage.
  Works in unarmed combat or Left Mouse Button attacks with a Slash damage weapon. Works much worse against armored opponents.
  Once harm is dealt, the sneakiness fades, retreating into swiftness, waiting for the next chance to rise.

  ### Loss of Surprise

  The opposite of Sneak Attack. In the silence of an opening, the ninja moves like a whisper in the wind.
  When the foe is knocked down, the Katana strike comes faster than the eye can follow. And unarmed, each attack will
  drain the opponent's stamina. Speed is their weapon, and the moment to strike is fleeting, like a shadow in the dark.

  ### Shadow Surge

  After a successful kill, the ninja's spirit sharpens and quickens. Their movement speed increases temporally,
  gliding through shadow and blood alike — unseen, unstoppable, and already gone before the next breath is drawn.

  ## Combo attacks

  ### Ninjutsu Takedown

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookHelp" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Only works with active Sneak Attack. Knocks the opponent down. Works better if performed from behind.

  ### Bite The Dust

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookHarm" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookGrab" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Temporarily knocks the opponent down.

  ### Dirty Kill

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookDisarm" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookDisarm" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Temporarily stuns a knocked down opponent.

</Document>
