<Document>

  # Ninjutsu

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingMaskNinja" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Ninjutsu is a [textlink="martial art" link="MartialArts"] thoroughly developed by the Spider Clan.
  Space Ninjas are true masters of this technique, yet Space Wizards may also unravel its secrets.
  Remember your four teachings. Never move around loud. Only strike when unseen. Patience prevails, haste fails. Death comes in silence.

  ## Special abilities

  ### Sneak Attack

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="EnergyKatana" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  In the shadow of stillness, the Ninja's strike shall echo with the force of two. Doubles the damage for next melee attack.
  Once harm is dealt, the sneakiness fades, retreating into swiftness, waiting for the next chance to rise.
  Enables Ninjutsu Takedown and Assassinate, disables Swift Strike.

  ### Loss of Surprise

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookLossOfSurprise" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  In the silence of an opening, the ninja moves like a whisper in the wind.
  Speed is their weapon, and the moment to strike is fleeting, like a shadow in the dark.
  Lasts 5 seconds. Disables Ninjutsu Takedown and Assassinate but enables Swift Strike.

  ### Escape Plan

  Your target has perished. It is time to leave and plan your next attack.

  After a successful kill, the ninja's spirit sharpens and quickens. Their movement speed increases temporally,
  gliding through shadow and blood alike — unseen, unstoppable, and already gone before the next breath is drawn.

  ## Combo attacks

  ### Assasinate

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookHarm" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Deals massive damage to target's chest if Sneak Attack is active. Damage is easily stopped by armor.
  Works in unarmed combat or Left Mouse Button attacks using a Slash damage weapon.

  ### Ninjutsu Takedown

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookHelp" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Only works with active Sneak Attack. Slows the opponent down significantly and mutes them.
  Works better if performed from behind.

  ### Swift Strike

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookHarm" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  When the foe is knocked down, melee weapon dealing slash strike comes faster than the eye can follow.
  And unarmed, each attack will drain the opponent's stamina. Only works with Loss of Surprise active.

  ### Bite The Dust

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookHarm" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookGrab" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Temporarily knocks the opponent down. As well as dealing blunt damage.

  ### Dirty Kill

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookDisarm" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookDisarm" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Temporarily stuns a knocked down opponent. Target cannot be stunned for longer than they are knocked down.

</Document>
