<Document>

  # Way of The Sleeping Carp

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SleepingCarpScroll" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  The Way of The Sleeping Carp, or simply the Sleeping Carp, is an ancient [textlink="martial art" link="MartialArts"] learned through intense study and meditation.
  It is modeled after the graceful movement, combat, and flow of Space Carp. Ancient masters of this art are rumored to have studied among great schools of space carp
  and survived, some have even befriended the aggressive creatures. This art is often utilized by zealots and extremists especially among The Syndicate.

  ## Special abilities

  Sleeping Carp users are better at Harm intent, as their unarmed attacks will deal extra damage to the opponent.

  ### Riptide Reflection

  Due to the graceful nature of this martial art, Sleeping Carp users are able to completely deflect almost all incoming
  projectiles. Whether ballistic or energy-based projectiles, hitscan shots or bolas, they effortlessly reflect them.
  However, explosives, knives, and syringes remain outside their control, slipping through the serene flow of their defense.

  ### Fellow Fish

  Users of the Sleeping Carp style move with the grace of the waters, in perfect harmony with Space Carp.
  These creatures, sensing the peaceful bond, will more often than not treat them as allies, not attacking them.
  This connection extends to other Carp-like beings, including Sharkminnows and even the mighty Space Dragons.

  ### Gun Gainsay

  Part of becoming a Master of Sleeping Carp is to take an oath to abstain from using guns. This includes regular guns
  and firearms attached to equipment such as mechs. It isn't quite clear why, however, it is thought that it allows the
  user to intensify their focus on perfect flow and deflection. Others believe that it is part of the drive of the master
  to further emulate the way of the Carp, to completely focus on the attack of the Carp: its [bold] Bite [/bold]. This does not prevent
  the practitioners of Sleeping Carp from throwing items, bolas, floor tiles, or even people, all useful ranged weapons.

  ## Combo attacks

  ### Keelhaul

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookHarm" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookGrab" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Kicks an opponent in the head, knocking them down and dealing both Slash and Stamina damage to them,
  unless they are already stunned. In that case, it will as well completely disarm the opponent.

  ### Crashing Waves Kick

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookHarm" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookDisarm" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Kicks the opponent square in the chest, sending them flying and dealing Slash damage. Only works on standing opponents.

  ### Gnashing Teeth

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookHarm" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookHarm" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Deals extra Slash damage, and makes the user shout to strike fear into their opponent's heart.

</Document>
