<Document>
  # Hydrakin

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobHydrakin" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Hydrakin are avian creatures with an odd appearance and an extreme tolerance for cold. Fluffy, exceptionally warm, and notoriously noisy, these birds originate from a desolate iceworld far beyond the normal limits of habitable space. Their home planet is locked in perpetual ice storms, dimly lit, and surrounded by liquid oxygen oceans beneath a frezon-heavy atmosphere—once thought entirely lifeless.

  Previously not meeting qualifications for sentience, the species was uplifted by Ullman Industries. Instead of being uplifted for integration or labor, Ullman pursued uplift as a proof-of-concept experiment to demonstrate its technological capability to investors. Once sapience and communication benchmarks were met, the project was declared a success, but the uplifted species itself was considered uneconomical to corporate interests.

  Transport disruptions, bluespace storms, and corporate negligence scattered Hydrakin shipments and colonies across the Colossus, leaving many outside Ullman control. Today, the Hydrakin exist as a partially uplifted, displaced species, struggling to adapt to a sector they were never meant to inhabit.


  Hydrakin bodies overheat extremely quickly in hot environments due to highly heat generating adaptations.

  Due to their unusual cheese shaped heads, they cannot wear glasses, both as a product of not having any visible eyes, and because its impossible to give prescription to a hydrakin.

  Hydrakin benefit from a sturdy frame and a dense cost of feathers, which makes them 10% more resistant to piercing damage and blunt damage.

  However, they do not do so well when sliced, taking 15% more slash damage.

  They severely dislike heat, taking 25% more heat damage, as it overheats them, and their dense coat does not do well with venting heat they gain.

  They are extremely resistant and highly adapted to cold environments, as well as mild resistance to low pressures.

  Hydrakin tails tend to vary, but most have hooks or prehensile strength. They are able to tail pull similarly to lizards, freeing a hand while dragging things.

  Hydrakin lungs have unique interactions with various exotic atmospheric gases, especially Frezon.

  Hydrakin have a special mix of semi-anaerobic blood which tolerates high cold, but gives them high heat production.

  Hydrakin can only eat raw foods, and have an allergy to onions or chocolatey food.

  When using or ingesting leporazine, Hydrakin bodies instead enter a state of cooling, and will lose body heat rather than stabilize from it, an unintended side effect of the drug.


</Document>
