<Document>
# Chaplain
There's something about the vast infinity of space that turns men to prayer... Especially if they get thrown into it without a space suit.


As a chaplain, you would ideally proselytize whatever crazy religion you've made up for that round over your headset. However, besides your office, the hellish crematorium next to your office, and the rarely used morgue, you have no access.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Bible"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Nullrod"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ArmamentsBeacon"/>
  </Box>

## Religions:
You are free to propagate any present day religions you know of, or even invent one of your own! Just make sure it doesn't go against NanoTrasen and its values, or you may well end up in the brig.

If you don't already have one, build an altar and find an offering to place on-top:

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarBananium"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarChaos"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarDruid"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarClock"/>
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarFangs"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarHeaven"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarConvertMaint"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarNanotrasen"/>
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarSpaceChristian"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarTechnology"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarToolbox"/>
  </Box>

These altars can be constructed by placing the following offerings atop your base convert altar:

- Bananium Altar: 1 x Bananium
- Chaos Altar: 1 x Plasma
- Druid Altar: 1 x Wooden Plank
- Fanged Altar: 1 x Raw Meat
- Heaven Altar: 1 x Templar Helmet
- Maints Altar: 1 x Budget Insulated Gloves
- Nanotrasen Altar: 1 x Plasteel
- Space-Christian Altar: 1 x Nun Hood
- Technology Altar: 1 x Capacitor
- Toolbox Altar: 1 x Toolbox
- Clockwork Altar: 1 x Small Power Cell
- Blue Altar: 1 x Makeshift Shield

## Holy Artefacts

### Armaments Beacon
Allows you to choose a set of armor. All armors have identical stats.

### Null Rod
The Null Rod is the chaplain's trusty tool, With it the chaplain is one of the most feared crew memebers for magical beings, and without it the chaplain is nothing.

  ### Null Rod [Default]
  Holds the power to transform into any form you desire, although don't write off the default nullrod as it is a great weapon without any gimmicks.

  Does good damage (10 blunt and 10 holy) at average speed.

  ### Atheist's Fedora [Nanotrasen Altar]
  The latest fasion among "cool" chaplain these days, it's fitted with special Nanotrasen patented boomerang technology so you won't have to worry about losing it.

  Deals low melee damage (5 slash and 10 holy) with average throwing damage (10 slash and 10 holy) with average attack speed.

  ### God Hand [Chaos Altar]
  Infuse your own hand with the power of the GODS replacing it with a Firey, Blazing, Holy hand.

  Deals good damage ([color=red]10 Heat[/color], 4 slash and 10 holy) at average speed with the added ability of applying fire stacks and instantly hard grabbing the target.

  ### Holy Claymore [Heaven Altar]
  The number one choice for space crusaders this holy sword has been one of the most reliable weapons throught out the history of space crusades.

  Right clicking with this weapon while wealding it shoots out a yellow bolt of holy energy.
  Hitting a enemy who is marked with the bolt will both deal more damage and [color=green]and heal you for twenty brute, and ten airloss[/color].

  Deals good damage (13 slash and 10 holy) It's melee speed is average with a 0.5 shots per second ranged bolt.

  ### Monk's Staff [Nature Altar]
  A wooden staff, Typically used to beat the literal and metaphorical Devil out of someone.
  Its real power lies in the staffs ability to deal stamina damage.

  Deals low damage (2.5 blunt and 6 holy, with an additional [color=blue]10 stamina[/color]) at a fast attack speed.

  ### His Holy Chainsaw [Toolbox Altar]
  Do you like chainsaws? Are you mildly insane? Then this is the nullrod for you, Completely replace your arm with a full on chainsaw and hack up those demons.

  Needs wielding, But deals low damage (2 blunt, 3 slash and 6 holy, With 20 structural to tear into places) at a very fast attack speed.

  ### Rosary [Space Christian Altar]

  For those who don't want to get their hands dirty, This nullrod has got the best utility out of all of them.
  Allows you to pray to it to heal in a decently large area while also dealing holy damage to unholy beings.

  Does little damage, (3 blunt and 10 holy) for both melee and area of effect hits.

  ### Casul & Jackal [Technology Altar]

  Why go through all the trouble of catching them when you can just shoot them.
  Comes in a pair of 2 pistols that can only be shot together, They may be reloaded by whispering a prayer into them.
  They do not block magical attacks.

  Each pistol does low damage, and comes in a special holster, deals (5 piercing and 4 holy per shot)

  ### Grey Emperor's Glove [Maintenance Altar]
  The tider GOD has chosen you to be his vessel, replace your hand with HIS and let HIS power flow through you.

  Allows you to use any tool you need(dosen't come with a welder) and is fully insulated.

  Deals good damage (14 holy and 9 blunt) with average attack speed.

  ### Arythmic Knife [Fanged Altar]
  knife of the speed addicts, randomly speeds and slows you down at intervals, between 0.6x move speed and 2.0x move speed.

  Average attack speed and lowish damage (9 slash and 10 holy)

  ### Honkmother's maw [Bananium Altar]

  Honkmother chosen, With this great power you must [bold]SLIP![/bold]
  Slips the target on hit (with a long cooldown for sliping)

  Average attack speed and lowish damage (10 blunt and 12 holy)

  ### Ratvarian Spear [Clockwork Altar]
  A spear scavanged and forged from the remains of the very dead clockwork god.
  A robust melee weapon with added range, and a good throwing one at that, tho it likes to stick to stuff when thrown and is pretty annoying to pull out.

  Average attack speed, and good damage (18 peircing, 10 holy, 25 peircing and 10 holy on throw)

  ### Bulwark [Blue Altar]

  Big shield not much to say here.
  Gives you the ability to dash, and knocks the target on hit back by 5 tiles.

  It blocks 15% of all damage unless planted, then its 100%. It does low damage (5 slash and 10 holy) at a slow speed.

### Enchanting

You can use your Bible and any Altar of your choosing to [textlink="enchant items." link="Enchanting"]

### Spirit Candles
You can craft a spirit candle by putting a candle on a skull. Spirit Candles are useful against evil spirits like Wraith.

When they are ignited, they create a 12x12 tile area that reveals evil spirits. It also has a special function when you use it in-hand.
By using it [bold]when an evil spirit is within(!!) your 12x12 area[/bold], it will make them corporeal.

It has 2 charges per spirit candle, and [bold]it only consumes a charge when you reveal the evil spirit[/bold].

It drops the skull once the candle has melted, so you can craft another one.

## Duties

- Church Services: Give sermons and sing hymns.
- Proselytizing: Most crew members are godless heathens, show them god's love.
- Burial Services: Security or Medical may require someone, or something... to be cremated, familiarise yourself with your Chapel so you can make things quick!
- [bold] Metaphysical Investigation: Most crew aren't aware of the threats posed by the unholy, be on the look out for anything suspicious. [/bold]

### Metaphysical Threats
As Chaplain you are the first line of defence against metaphysical threats, [bold] ready your Null Rod - the time is now. [/bold]

[color=red][bold] Use of excessive force against targets which you cannot confirm are metaphysical threats may land you in trouble with the law, use caution and investigate carefully. [/bold][/color]

</Document>
