<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Aiden <28298836+Aidenkrz@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 ArtisticRoomba <145879011+ArtisticRoomba@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 SX_7 <sn1.test.preria.2002@gmail.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
  # Gasses
  Gasses are a critical part of the station's operation.
  You may know them as the stuff you breathe, but they are also used in many other ways.

  Gasses have certain properties that make them useful for different tasks.
  Atmospherics can also synthesize exotic gasses from other gasses, which can be used for special purposes.

  ## Oxygen
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="OxygenCanister" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="OxygenTank" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DoubleEmergencyOxygenTank" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ExtendedEmergencyOxygenTank" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="EmergencyOxygenTank" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  A common gas, used by most species on the station to breathe.

  Oxygen is an oxidizer, which means it supports combustion.
  This makes it both useful when fusing gasses in a burn chamber, and dangerous when mixed with flammable gasses.

  ## Nitrogen
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="NitrogenCanister" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="NitrogenTank" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DoubleEmergencyNitrogenTank" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ExtendedEmergencyNitrogenTank" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="EmergencyNitrogenTank" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  An inert gas, used in part with oxygen to create a breathable atmosphere.

  Nitrogen is very stable and comprises most of a standard breathable atmosphere.

  Some species like Slimes breathe nitrogen, with the Vox species requiring strictly nitrogen to breathe.

  ## Air Mix
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AirCanister" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AirTank" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  A mixture of gasses that is breathable to most species on the station.
  It consists of 21% oxygen and 79% nitrogen.


  ## Carbon Dioxide
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CarbonDioxideCanister" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  A waste gas produced by most species on the station. A common byproduct of combustion.

  Despite seeming useless, some departments use it in their line of work.

  ## Water Vapor
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WaterVaporCanister" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  A common gas, produced by the burning of plasma and other processes.

  Water vapor has a good specific heat capacity compared to other gasses, making it useful for moving heat around.

  ## Plasma
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PlasmaCanister" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  A highly flammable gas that is used in many processes on the station.

  Engineering uses this gas to generate power and create exotic gasses.

  Burning it generates a lot of heat, as well as gas byproducts such as carbon dioxide, water vapor, and tritium, depending on the efficiency of the burn.

  Plasma gas also has a good specific heat capacity, making it useful for moving heat around.

  ## Tritium
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="TritiumCanister" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  Tritium is a clear, green gas that is highly flammable, radioactive, and combusts when in contact with oxygen, making it very helpful when running the [color=#a4885c]TEG[/color].
  It can be made by burning 1% Plasma and 96% or more Oxygen in the Burn Chamber (Ideal ratio is rough 3% Plasma to 97% Oxygen when injected into an ongoing burn chamber).
  You can extract this gas through scrubbers to prevent further combustion in pipes.

  ## Pluoxium
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PluoxiumCanister" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  Pluoxium is a non-reactive Oxygen substitute that delivers eight times as much O2 to the bloodstream, with as little 3 kPa minimum pressure required for internals.

  Pluoxium may be created by exposing O2, CO2 and Tritium together in an exothermic reaction between 50 K and 273 K. Furthermore, Pluoxium is also created by the Supermatter, when Oxygen and CO2 are present.

  ## Frezon
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FrezonCanister" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  A highly sought after gas, due to the difficulty in creating it and its many properties.

  It has an extremely high specific heat capacity, making it excellent for moving large amounts of heat around.

  Frezon can combine in the air with nitrogen to create nitrous oxide, alongside cooling down the air significantly to below freezing temperatures.

  If you're looking to create this gas yourself, here's what you need to know:
  - The reaction requires 90% Oxygen, 8% Nitrogen, and 2% Tritium at or below 73.15 K.
  - Nitrogen is required as a catalyst for the reaction. The amount of nitrogen consumed is dependent on the efficiency of the reaction.
  - The closer to 73.15 K, the more frezon is produced, and the less nitrogen is consumed.

  Remember, atmospherics is all about experimentation and process optimization. Try it until you get it right!

  ## Nitrous Oxide
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="NitrousOxideCanister" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="EmergencyFunnyOxygenTank" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  A recreational and waste gas, produced by slimes and the combination of frezon and nitrogen.

  ## BZ
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BZCanister" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  BZ gas is a potent hallucinogenic, as well as a sleeping agent for slimes. It's made from Plasma and Nitroux Oxide. It is toxic to breathe and causes respiratory irritation and coughing. BZ sees frequent use as an ingredient in more complex gas reactions.

  ## Healium
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="HealiumCanister" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  Healium is a red gas, formed by BZ and Frezon in cold environments, which acts as a strong sleeping agent, while healing burns, bruises, and toxin damage. Excessive use will lead to inebriation.

  ## Ammonia
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AmmoniaCanister" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  A gas produced by the decomposition of bodies. Can be condensed to create ammonia, which can be used to make space cleaner.

  ## Nitrium
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="NitriumCanister" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  Made from Tritium, Nitrogen and BZ, Nitrium is a gaseous stimulant that when inhaled can enhance speed and endurance. At lower concentrations Nitrium will increase your top running speed while healthy and unimpaired. Additionally, at slightly higher concentrations, breathing Nitrium will prevent drowsiness. At high concentrations breathing it will begin to shut down a person's lungs, causing asphyxiation.
  Nitrium degrades into nitrogen and water vapor on contact with room temperature oxygen. This reaction can produce a good deal of heat, making the station uncomfortably warm in the event of a leak.

  ##Healium
  Healium is a red gas, formed in cold environments, which acts as a strong sleeping agent, while healing burns, bruises, and toxin damage. Excessive use will lead to inebriation.
  It can be made by combining 91% Frezon and 9% BZ in an exothermic reaction.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BZCanister"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FrezonCanister"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasVentScrubber"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="HealiumCanister"/>
  </Box>

  ## Nitrium
  Nitrium is a gaseous stimulant that when inhaled can enhance speed and endurance. At lower concentrations Nitrium will increase your top running speed while healthy and unimpaired. Additionally, at slightly higher concentrations, breathing Nitrium will prevent drowsiness. At high concentrations breathing it will begin to shut down a person's lungs, causing asphyxiation.
  It can be made by combining 47.5% Nitrogen, 47.5% Tritium, and 5% BZ at or above 1500 K, with higher temperature giving greater efficiency.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BZCanister"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="TritiumCanister"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="NitrogenCanister"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasVentScrubber"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="NitriumCanister"/>
  </Box>

  Nitrium degrades into nitrogen and hydrogen on contact with room temperature oxygen. This reaction can produce a good deal of heat, making the station uncomfortably warm in the event of a leak.

  ##Hydrogen
  Hydrogen is a highly flammable but non-toxic gas that burns similarly to tritium, making it useful as a fuel source. It is produced by electrolyzing water vapor with an electrolyzer machine to produce hydrogen and oxygen.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WaterVaporCanister"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Electrolyzer"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasVentScrubber"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="HydrogenCanister"/>
  </Box>

  When mixed with BZ at temperatures below 273 K and pressures above 10 MPa, hydrogen can form metal hydrogen, a rare material. Handle hydrogen carefully to prevent fires or explosions, and store canisters securely.

  ##Proto-Nitrate
  Proto-Nitrate is a highly reactive, non-toxic gas. Combine 1 mole hydrogen with 0.1 moles pluoxium to yield 1.1 moles proto-nitrate exothermically, best at 5000-10000K. It reacts with hydrogen or tritium to adjust proto-nitrate or produce hydrogen, and with BZ at 260-280K to yield nitrogen, helium, and plasma. Handle carefully to avoid leaks.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="HydrogenCanister"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PluoxiumCanister"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasVentScrubber"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ProtoNitrateCanister"/>
  </Box>

  ##Zauker
  Zauker is a deadly gas if inhaled. Produce it by combining 0.2 moles hyper-noblium with 1 mole nitrium to yield 1 mole zauker exothermically. It decomposes with nitrogen into 0.3 moles oxygen and 0.7 moles nitrogen per mole zauker, also exothermic and inhibited similarly. Store securely to prevent leaks.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="NitriumCanister"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="HyperNobliumCanister"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasVentScrubber"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ZaukerCanister"/>
  </Box>

  ##Halon
  Halon suppresses fires by consuming oxygen, at a ratio of 20 moles oxygen per 1 mole halon, above 343.15 K in an endothermic reaction, producing carbon dioxide. It's made in an exothermic reaction by electrolyzing BZ, yielding 2 moles halon and 0.2 moles oxygen per mole BZ. Use cautiously to avoid oxygen depletion.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BZCanister"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Electrolyzer"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasVentScrubber"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="HalonCanister"/>
  </Box>

  ##Helium
  Helium is an inert, invisible gas produced as a byproduct of other reactions. It has minimal use in atmospherics, so scrub it to avoid diluting other gases.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasVentScrubber"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="HeliumCanister"/>
  </Box>

  ##Anti-Noblium
  Anti-Noblium is a rare gas with niche uses, produced by electrolyzing hyper-noblium below 150 K, yielding 0.5 moles anti-noblium per mole hyper-noblium. Store carefully to preserve hyper-noblium stocks for other reactions.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="HyperNobliumCanister"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Electrolyzer"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasVentScrubber"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AntiNobliumCanister"/>
  </Box>

</Document>
