<Document>
  # Brigmedic SOP
  This is the list of procedures, responsibilities, and duties of the [color=#ba292c][bold]Brigmedic[/bold][/color] of this station.

  <ColorBox>
    <Box>
      For the purposes of Alert Escalation: Treat higher alerts as if they are still on the previous alert level. (Yellow Alert is Blue Alert if it was Blue Alert prior.) Furthermore, treat Delta, Gamma, Epsilon, and Violet Alert as Red Alert.
    </Box>
  </ColorBox>

  ## Green Alert
  1. The Brigmedic must provide emergency medical care to prisoners, crew, and most importantly, Security personnel.

  2. The Brigmedic is not to leave the Security or Medical departments except to move between the two.

  <Box>Exception is made to faciliate movement between the two departments, to rescue injured persons, if warden/HOS permission is granted, in pursuit, or on red alert.</Box>

  3. The Brigmedic is permitted to carry a standard duty weapon, as well as their melee weapon. This weapon should only be used defensively to protect the brigmedic and their patients.

  4. The Brigmedic is permitted to assist the medical department in healing, protection, and arrest. However, you are to return to Security immediately should you be ordered to.

  <Box>When operating under the Medical department, the Brigmedic is to follow orders given by the Chief Medical Officer in regards to patient care and treatment, within reason. Special Circumstances may change this.</Box>

  ## Blue Alert
  1. Guidelines 1 and 4 are carried over from [color=#388c34]Green Alert[/color].

  2. Guideline 2 remains in effect, unless the Head of Security authorizes and requests the Brigmedic to patrol with the Security Officers to provide urgent medical care to them.

  3. Guideline 3 remains in effect, long guns may be carried if permission is granted by the Head Of Security. Your priority remains healing regardless.

  ## Red Alert
  1. Guidelines 1 and 4 are carried over from [color=#388c34]Green Alert[/color].

  2. Brigmedic is given the same authority and rights as Security Officers, and are now permitted to carry long guns, however, healing should remain the Brigmedic's top priority.

  3. The Brigmedic is now permitted to leave the Security and Medical departments to preform their duties.
</Document>
