<Document>
# Brigmedic SOP
This is the list of procedures, responsibilities, and duties of the [color=#ba292c][bold]Brigmedic[/bold][/color] of this station.

<ColorBox>
  <Box>
    For the purposes of Alert Escalation: Treat higher alerts as if they are still on the previous alert level. (Yellow Alert is Blue Alert if it was Blue Alert prior.) Furthermore, treat Delta, Gamma, Epsilon, and Violet Alert as Red Alert.
  </Box>
</ColorBox>

[color=#ba292c][bold]The Brigmedic[/bold][/color] is permitted to carry their shift-start equipment, but should follow escalation procedures and refrain from using lethals.

## Green Alert

1. The Brigmedic is held to the same guidelines and responsibilities as the [textlink="Paramedic" link="DoctorIntern SOP"]; with exceptions that they are to cater to Security Personnel and Prisoners over regular station personnel.

2. The Brigmedic is to follow the same guidelines as [textlink="Security Officers" link="OfficerCadet SOP"] for [color=#388c34]Green Alert[/color]

3. The Brigmedic is permitted, at the discretion of the [color=#ba292c][bold]Warden[/bold][/color] or the [color=#ba292c][bold]Head of Security[/bold][/color], to assist Security Officers with all Patrol Duties. This includes stops, searches, and arrests as per the current Alert Code.
<Box>However, The priority of the Brigmedic is the well-being of Security personel and Prisoners, and without sufficient cause, The Brigmedic may not leave untreated prisoners in the security department.</Box>

4. The Brigmedic is to respond to demands from [color=#ba292c][bold]Warden[/bold][/color] for Security Treatment with immediate priority.

5. The Brigmedic is to prioritize Security Personnel over others.

6. The Brigmedic is to prioritize treatment of Prisoners over regular Medical Personnel.

7. The Brigmedic is not permitted to unholster lethal weapons on green alert, however, they may choose to carry one at the discretion of the [color=#ba292c][bold]Warden[/bold][/color]

8. The Brigmedic may perform, at the Prisoner's request, any type of surgery or body modification asked for on the requesting Prisoner.

9. The Brigmedic may NOT perform any type of surgery or body modification on a Prisoner if the requester is OTHER than the prisoner. This does not include general treatment surgery, which may be performed at any time.
<Box>An exception is made if the prisoners are acting overly hostile or attempting to breach the cell in order to escape, or if the surgery is deemed required, such as extraction of foreign and or dangerous objects.</Box>

10. The Brigmedic must ensure that admitted prisoners upon release are reasonably healthy and have any body modifications to their person reversed, or healed.
<Box>This does not include the return of any contraband or dangerous objects found inside or within the prisoner </Box>

  11. The Brigmedic is not permitted to wear their hardsuit during green alet, if there is no present threat or need for it, such as spacing.

  ## Blue Alert
  1. All Guidelines carry over from [color=#388c34]Green Alert[/color].

  2. Additionally, The Brigmedic follows the same guidelines as [textlink="Security Officers" link="OfficerCadet SOP"] for [color=#1b67a5]Blue Alert[/color].

  3. In the case of understaffing, the Brigmedic may leave non-severely injured prisoners untended to inside the security department, in order to assist Security Officers.
  <Box>This does not apply to prisoners dead, or in a critical state. They must be tended to before leaving the security department.</Box>

  4. The Brigmedic is permitted to perform surgery on Prisoners at the Brigmedic's discretion, given there is a provable need. Such as a chest cavity search, implantation of devices.

  ## Red Alert
  1. Guidelines 1,2,3,4,5,7,8,9,10 carry over from [color=#388c34]Green[/color] and all guidelines from [color=#1b67a5]Blue[/color].

  2. Additionally, The Brigmedic follows the same guidelines as [textlink="Security Officers" link="OfficerCadet SOP"] for [color=#ba292c]Red Alert[/color].

  3. The Brigmedic, may prioritize other personel above prisoners for treatment, given there is sufficient threat to them, and there aren't any medical personel present.
  <Box>However Security must still be prioritized above others.</Box>


</Document>
