<Document>
# Sergeant (Senior Officer) SOP
This is the list of procedures, responsibilities, and duties of the [color=#1b67a5][bold]Sergeant[/bold][/color] of this station.

<ColorBox>
  <Box>
    For the purposes of Alert Escalation: Treat higher alerts as if they are still on the previous alert level. (Yellow Alert is Blue Alert if it was Blue Alert prior.) Furthermore, treat Delta, Gamma, Epsilon, and Violet Alert as Red Alert.
  </Box>
</ColorBox>

The [color=#1b67a5][bold]Sergeant[/bold][/color] is permitted to carry their shift-start equipment, but should follow escalation procedures and refrain from using lethals.

The Sergeant is a senior role to all officers and cadets, but reports to the Warden and HoS.

For purposes of LoP (Line of Progression), the Sergeant should always be first in line to fill as acting HoS or Warden.

The Sergeant shares all responsibilities of security officers, but is to prioritize training, directing, advising, and leading officers and cadets. To this end, the Security Officer SoP should be consulted for escalation procedures in regards to alert.

## Green Alert
1. The Sergeant is to prioritize training and oversight of officers over the standard duties of security.

2. The Sergeant is permitted to carry a standard disabler, a flash, a trench whistle, a flashbang, and their signature Nanotrasen approved ceremonial weapon.
<Box>While permitted to carry their unique ceremonial weapon, its use should be for ceremony and training only.</Box>

3. The Sergeant is also permitted to carry all standard security items appropriate to an officer.

4. The Sergeant should have a comprehensive understanding of spacelaw, and is to be called upon in times of need for advice, legal council, and court. To this end, the Sergeant can conduct sentencing in the absence of a warden.

5. The Sergeant must comply with all LEGAL orders from the HOS and Warden. In situations where the HoS or Warden is in violation of spacelaw, the Sergeant is expected to work with the Captain and NTR to appropriately handle the breach of conduct.

6. The Sergeant  must follow the same guidelines as the Warden for Armory equipment, portable flashers and deployable barriers. Also in times of need the Sergeant is to help the Warden with any reasonable need.

7. The Sergeant  is not permitted to collect equipment from the Armory to carry on their person.

8. The Sergeant is permitted to wear any reasonable security apparel for the purposes of training and ceremony.

9. The Sergeant is permitted to wear a gas mask.

10. Sentences given by the Sergeant may be overruled by the Warden or HoS if they do not match the sentencing chart within spacelaw.

11. The Sergeant is NOT allowed to use their whistle outside of training and ceremony.

## Blue Alert
1. All Guidelines carry over from [color=#388c34]Green Alert[/color].
<Box>The exception being that the ceremonial weapon may be used if needed.</Box>

2. The Sergeant is allowed to use their whistle as necessary.

3. The Sergeant is to prioritize leading from the front so that HoS can focus on core and command control and security, and the Warden can focus on the armory integrity.

## Red Alert
1. All Guidelines carry over from [color=#388c34]Green Alert[/color] and [color=#1b67a5]Blue Alert[/color].

2. The Head of Sergeant may also wear a hardsuit if necessary.

3. The Sergeant is to prioritize filling in for the HoS or Warden in the event of incapacitation or casualty.

</Document>