<Document>
  # Roleplay Rule 5-1
  ## Antagonists must exercise acceptable collateral damage.
  This rule is not intended to disallow reasonable steps taken to complete your objectives. As an antagonist, you can always kill in bona fide self defense. Taking steps to permanently round remove many people who are no longer an immediate threat to you is not permitted, even if it is done to prevent yourself from being discovered.

  This rule is not intended to disallow all antagonist activity unrelated to objectives. Antagonists may cause a level of disruption to the station that is proportional to their objectives, even if it is unrelated to their objectives. As an antagonist, killing a single person in a round is not on its own be a violation of this rule.

  ## Traitors
  Traitors should only kill people who are either their named objectives or are posing an active threat in self defense. Otherwise, they should not be killing indiscriminately. Killing non-targets to acquire gear or access while not in active conflict with them is also not permitted. Baiting non-targets into conflict solely to get their gear or access is absolutely not permitted.

  Traitors are expected to employ subterfuge and stealth to complete their objectives. They should not be causing massive damage in order to complete their objectives unless it can be fully justified.

  Remember; just because Security and Command are present doesn't mean they're actively a threat until it is abundantly clear.

  Acceptable:
  - Permanently round removing people who you have the objective to kill.
  - Killing active threats to you (usually Security) in self defense.
  - Sabotaging department power to make a steal objective easier to accomplish.
  - Looting gear and/or access from a non-target who was actively pursuing you of which you killed in self defense.

  Prohibited:
  - Killing any non-target who is not an active threat to you.
  - Killing any non-target to acquire their gear and/or access who is not an active threat to you.
  - Permanently round removing people who are NOT your objective(s) to kill.
  - Causing massive station damage that easily results in collateral deaths of multiple non-targets.
  - Setting up an electrified grille in maintenance and using it to kill anyone who walks into it with the hope that one of your objectives will be one of them.
  - Sabotaging power station-wide 10 minutes into the round to make a steal objective easier to accomplish.

  ## Heretics
  Heretics are generally permitted to kill indiscriminately, as they often need body parts that can only be acquired by killing and gibbing people. However, there are alternative means that would be more acceptable and interesting for RP. Still, they can kill anyone they want to kill. Ideally, though, they should still be targeted murders and not large scale attacks or means of sabotage that result in more deaths than necessary.

  ## Changelings
  Changelings require biomass and their objectives are to extract genetic material; so it's practically their entire purpose to kill. There are alternative methods to acquire biomass and genetic material that doesn't require being the direct cause of death for another person, but they are still fully permitted to kill anyone they want to kill. Preferably, Changelings should not be causing massive damage in order to complete their objectives and instead employ a level of subterfuge and stealth; but they are free to target anyone they like.

  ## Nuclear Operatives
  Nuclear Operatives have full license to kill anyone they see. Their entire purpose is to nuke the station and cause as much collateral damage as possible. They can kill anyone they want to kill and cause as much damage as they want to cause.

  ## Space Dragons & Carps
  Space Dragons and Carps are naturally expected to attack everyone. There's no discussion here!

  ## Thief
  Thieves are pacifists. They cannot directly attack anyone and should not elaborately find a way to kill someone indirectly. They can still sabotage department power to make getting their targets easier - and naturally can thieve useful items that may not be their objectives but assist in completing them.
</Document>
